Inventory of the Phillip D. Sprouse papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Phillip D. Sprouse papers
1945-1964
74034
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 18 envelopes (2.6 linear feet)
Printed matter, clippings, maps, invitations, programs, diplomatic list, and photographs, relating to American relations with China and Cambodia, the Marshall Mission of 1945-1946, and cultural and political conditions in Cambodia.
Sprouse, Philip D., 1906-1977.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American diplomat; member of George C. Marshall and Albert C. Wedemeyer Missions to China, 1945-1947; ambassador to Cambodia, 1962-1964.
Scope and Content of Collection
Printed matter, clippings, maps, invitations, programs, diplomatic list, and photographs, relating to American relations with China and Cambodia, the Marshall Mission of 1945-1946, and cultural and political conditions in Cambodia.
Marshall, George Catlett, 1880-1959.; Wedemeyer, Albert C. (Albert Coady), 1896-1989.; Cambodia--Foreign relations--United States.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--History--Civil War, 1945-1949.; Diplomats--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Cambodia.; United States--Foreign relations--China.
- Printed matter, clippings, maps, invitations, programs, and diplomatic list, relating to American relations with China and Cambodia, the Marshall Mission of 1945-1946, and cultural and political conditions in Cambodia. (Box 1-2)
- 23 photos of the Marshall Mission to China, including George C. Marshall, Mao Tse-Tung, Chou Enlai, Walter Robertson, Huang-Hua, Gen. Cheng Kai-Min, Gen. Yeh Ching-Ying, Chang Chih-Chung, Chu-Teh, Yen Hsi-Chan, 1946 (Folder A)
- 1 photo of Philip Sprouse at the United Nations conference as Liaison officer, State Department, 1945 (Folder B)
- 37 photos of the A.C. Wedemeyer (JADE) Mission to China, including A.C. Wedemeyer, B.G. Ralph Wooten, etc., undated (Folder C)
- 1 photo of Prince Bov-Loc with Prince Siahanouk, 1952 (Folder D)
- 1 photo of Philip Sprouse with the ambassador of the Dominican Republic, Brussels, circa 1954 (Folder E)
- 8 photos of Philip Sprouse at Angor-Wat, undated (Folder F)
- 1 photo of Philip Sprouse being sworn in as ambassador to Cambodia, includes Dean Rusk, undated (Folder G)
- 3 photos of Philip Sprouse presenting credentials as U.S. ambassador to Cambodia, undated (Folder mH)
- 123 photos of Philip Sprouse as Amb. to Cambodia, official ceremonies, social functions, etc, undated (Folder I-L)
- 36 photos of Prince Siahanouk, undated (Box M)
- 16 photos of Gen. Maxwell Taylor during his visit to Cambodia, 1962 (Folder N)
- 4 photos of Sen. Mike Mansfield during his visit to Cambodia, 1963 (Folder O)
- 19 photos of riots against U.S.A.I.D. offices, Cambodia, December 1963 (Folder P)
- 2 portrait photos of Philip Sprouse, undated (Folder Q)
- 512 miscellaneous and duplicate photos, undated (Folder R)